## James R. Priest

5111 Princess Anne Road, La Canada, CA 91011 • Cell 626-240-9970 Email james-priest@outlook.com • Website https://james-priest.github.io

#### **SUMMARY**

Full Stack React, .NET, Node.js, DB Developer with 20 years of experience building web & mobile applications.

#### **SKILLS**

Web: HTML5, CSS3, DOM, Bootstrap, Semantic-UI Languages: JavaScript, C#, SQL, RegEx, VB.NET Frameworks: React, Redux, ASP.NET, Node.js, jQuery Data: Stored procs, functions, triggers, Relational/NoSQL

**Design:** Responsive UI, Accessible & Usable UX

Hosting: Netlify, Heroku, Azure Web

**HTML5 APIs:** IDB, Cache API, Fetch API, Promise API **Version Control:** Git, GitHub, SVN, Azure DevOps **Build:** NPM, Grunt, Gulp, Webpack, Parcel, Yeoman **IDEs:** VS Code, Visual Studio, SSMS, MySQL WB

Cloud: Azure DevOps, AWS, RestDB.io Static Site Gen: Gatsby, Jekyll, GitHub Pages

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

## Senior Web Application Developer / Technology Director

04/2006 - 03/2017

Pasadena, CA

Velodea

- Served as Solutions Architect, Programming Lead, and Database Developer for digital marketing firm.
- Successfully built hundreds of website solutions and marketing campaigns for Fortune 500 companies including Shell, Qualcomm, Sprint, Maserati, Fox, Miramax, ABC, J. Walter Thompson, & Edelman.
- Designed large-scale medical management system to track & schedule education of 85,000 students.

## **Lead Developer & Founder**

La Canada, CA

devAware Technology Solutions

07/2002 - 03/2006

- Excelled in building custom Web, Windows, & .NET application systems for various corporate clients.
- Hired by Sony to build advanced kiosk application for VIAO laptops. Had successful nationwide rollout.
- Engineered web & desktop platform to promote major motion picture releases for Fox & Miramax.

## **Lead Software Developer**

Milan, Italy, Los Angeles, CA

The Velodea Group / Bleu22 Studios

07/2000 – 07/2002

- Led the product development team of multi-national digital start-up with offices in Milan & Los Angeles.
- Developed real-time web analytics platform to provide behavioral tracking & custom reporting.
- Built proprietary asset & client management system. Licensed by Sony, Qualcomm, & Shell Oil.

## **Release Program Manager**

Redmond, WA

Microsoft

11/1998 – 06/2000

- Designed mission-critical app suite to manage thousands of software releases to the web each month.
- Build web-based training system to provide CBT to employees and non-technical business owners.
- Engineered tracking & query system to manage media shipments of software to third-party vendors.

## **EDUCATION**

DeVry University	Pomona, CA
Bachelor of Computer Information Systems (BSc CIS)	Graduated with Honors – GPA 3.52/4.00

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

React Nanodegree (React, Redux, React Native), Udacity	6-month term	June 2019
Google Mobile Web Specialist Nanodegree, Udacity	6-month term	October 2018
JavaScript Algorithms & Data Structures, freeCodeCamp	300 hours	December 2017
Responsive Web Design, freeCodeCamp	300 hours	July 2017

# James R. Priest

5111 Princess Anne Road, La Canada, CA 91011 • Cell 626-240-9970 Email james-priest@outlook.com • Website https://james-priest.github.io

#### **RECENT PROJECTS**

#### **Mobile Flashcards App**

June 2019

GitHub: <a href="https://bit.ly/2KqJE3i">https://bit.ly/2KqJE3i</a> Live Demo: <a href="https://bit.ly/2Irc8aY">https://bit.ly/2Irc8aY</a>



React Native, Redux, React Navigation, Redux Thunk, Expo, Animations, Notifications

## **Triathlon Fitness Tracker**

May 2019

GitHub: <a href="https://bit.ly/2MTVhSc">https://bit.ly/2MTVhSc</a> Live Demo: <a href="https://bit.ly/2FhBE06">https://bit.ly/2FhBE06</a>



React Native, Redux, React Navigation, Geolocation, Notifications, Expo

## **Would You Rather Game**

**April 2019** 

GitHub: <a href="https://bit.ly/2MVL2Ng">https://bit.ly/2MVL2Ng</a> Live Demo: <a href="https://bit.ly/2RkLflc">https://bit.ly/2RkLflc</a>



React, Redux, React Router, Redux Thunk, Auth, REST API, RestDB, Semantic-UI-React

## **Restaurant Review App**

December 2018

GitHub: <a href="https://bit.ly/2x1xwwL">https://bit.ly/2x1xwwL</a> Live Demo: <a href="https://bit.ly/2KYE0EJ">https://bit.ly/2KYE0EJ</a>



PWA, IndexedDB, Cache API, Promise API, Service Worker, REST API, RestDB

## **CSS Grid Learning App**

June 2018

GitHub: <a href="https://bit.ly/2WR0Gcz">https://bit.ly/2WR0Gcz</a> Live Demo: <a href="https://bit.ly/2KpZ3AB">https://bit.ly/2KpZ3AB</a>



JavaScript ES6, CSS3 Animations, RegEx, Advanced DOM Manipulation

## **Weather Forecast App**

March 2018

GitHub: <a href="https://bit.ly/2IphkM8">https://bit.ly/2IphkM8</a>
Live Demo: <a href="https://bit.ly/2MRbgQP">https://bit.ly/2MRbgQP</a>



HTML5, Geolocation API, Semantic UI, CSS3 Animations, Async Web API